Guide to the Tijuana Bibles Collection, 1930-1998 RL.01295
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Tijuana Bibles collection
1930s-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
RL.01295
3 Linear Feet 500 items
Tijuana Bibles, also known as eight-pagers or dirty little books, were small eight-page publications of cartoon erotica and pornography that became popular during the 1930s and 1940s. This collection includes about 400 Tijuana Bibles, some of them duplicates; a few folders of erotica drawings and drafts by an unknown artist; and printed material about Tijuana Bibles, published from the 1970s through the 1990s.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Tijuana Bibles Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase from Rulon-Miller Books in July 2010 and September 2012. Updated January 2013, January 2017, and April 2017 with small additions.
Historical Note
Tijuana bibles are small, cheaply-made, pornographic publications. Also known as dirty little books or eight-pagers, Tijuana bibles emerged in the 1930s and remained popular through the 1940s, finally disappearing in the post-World War II period. Being underground erotic publications, there were no designated publishers or organizations creating the books; despite that, each adheres to a fairly consistent format. They average about 3x5 inches in size, and are eight pages in length, bound between covers by a staple. Images are cheaply printed on poor-quality paper by mimeograph, usually in black and white, occasionally incorporating the color red. The book's cover also serves as a title page, introducing the main character and sometimes an author's pen name (which is usually a sexual double entendre). Nearly every bible is undated and by an anonymous author.
Tijuana bible artists tended to draw their characters from mainstream newspaper comics, such as Popeye or Little Orphan Annie; politicians or celebrities from the day, such as Greta Garbo or Mae West; or American folklore or culture, such as a travelling salesman or an unemployed secretary. Although the books are extremely graphic in nature, there is also a consistent presence of humor, with the last page typically serving as a punch line.
Collection Overview
The Tijuana Bibles Collection consists of about 400 Tijuana bibles, some printed material about the bibles and the phenomenon as a whole, and an anonymous author's sketches and drawings of characters and plots.
The Tijuana bibles include a wide range of characters, many inspired by (or lifted from) mainstream media and celebrities. The most frequently used characters were from newspaper comic strips, including Andy Gump, Betty Boop, Blondie and Dagwood, Dick Tracy, Ella Cinders, Dumb Dora, Wimpy, Pete the Tramp, Tillie the Toiler, and Popeye. Other bibles include generic figures such as travelling salesmen (including a vacuum cleaner man, a book salesman, a radio salesmen, and so on); parodies of real people, including Nazis, boxer Joe Louis, and other celebrities; or versions of popular movie heroines, such as Snow White or Mae West.
The collection held in Rubenstein Library consists largely of Tijuana bibles, but also include other small pornographic cartoon or comic joke books, similar in design and in manufacturing quality, but not entirely true to the "traditional" form of a Tijuana bible. There are also Tijuana bible reproductions in this series.
The manuscript materials accompanying the bibles consist of drafts and sketches for two strips, one featuring Wahoo and the other featuring Li'l Abner and Daisy Mae. Also included is a draft of Fritzi Ritz in 'Kisses for Sale'. This series also includes pornographic drawings of generic female characters, some with and some without text. These do not appear to be taken from any particular Tijuana bible. All of the manuscript material is anonymous and undated.
Finally, the collection also includes a series of books about Tijuana bibles, compiled by the collector, including reprints of some of the bibles as well as essays or historical introductions to the genre. These books were published between 1971 and 1998.
Collection Arrangement
The Tijuana bibles have been arranged in alphabetical order by title. Please do a Control-Find search if you are looking for all Tijuana bibles featuring a certain character. Author pen names have been included when given on the book.
Erotic comic books, strips, etc. -- United States; Underground comic books, strips, etc. -- United States; Tijuana bibles; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Tijuana Bibles, 1
  - Adam and Eve in Big Discovery (Box 1)
  - The Adventures of a Fuller Brush Man: The Amorous Mrs. Twirp (Box 1)
  - The Adventures of a Fuller Brush Man: Dizzy Desires (Box 1)
  - The Adventures of a Fuller Brush Man: Easy Pickins (Box 1)
  - The Adventures of a Fuller Brush Man: Hot Pants (Box 1)
  - The Adventures of a Fuller Brush Man: Obliging Lady (Box 1)
  - The Adventures of a Fuller Brush Man: Torrid Tess (Box 1)
  - Al Capone in The Interview, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Alexander Smart Esq. in Tit for Tat, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Alley Oop in The Rescue (Box 1)
  - Alice Fay and The Ritz Brothers in Three of a Kind, by Phelan Heann (Box 1)
  - Andy Gump, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Presenting Andy Gump in Dreaming, by Fuller P. Slopjar (Box 1)
  - Andy Gump Has an Unusual Piece (Box 1)
  - Andy Gump Pays the Rent (Box 1)
  - Annie Goes Down on the Farm (Box 1)
  - Appo in Haunted (Box 1)
  - The Auto Salesman, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Archie featuring Reggie in "Archies Rival Gets Fucked" (Box 1)
  - Archie in Miss Grundy Gets Plowed (Box 1)
  - Archie in Teaches His Teacher (Box 1)
  - Artists and Models (Box 1)
  - Arthur Treacher in Breakfast in Bed (Box 1)
  - Bad Bill Snatches a Piece of Plunder (Box 1)
  - Balls Lost in the Rough, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Batman in It's A Crime (Box 1)
  - The Great Big Man from the South, starring Barney Google (Box 1)
  - Barney Google in Horse Flesh, by V. Fuzzynuts, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Benny Snooks in the Hay Loft 8, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Benny and his Bantam, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Benny Does it Without Words! (Box 1)
  - Betty Boop in Betty Steps Out, by Regina Doosh, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Betty Boop in Flesh, by Iva Crustycrotch (Box 3)
  - Betty Boop in Hot Pants (Box 1)
  - Big Chief Returns from Big City (Box 1)
  - Blondie, by U. Groan and I. Grunt, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Blondie in Alexander and Cookie Grow Up (Box 1)
  - Blondie in Dagwood's Delight (Box 1)
  - Blondie in Lonely, by Berna Pantz (Box 1)
  - Blondie in Suction Cunt Susie (Box 1)
  - Bonnie Parker in Amputated, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Boob McNutt (Box 1)
  - Boob McNutt in The Demonstrator, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - The Book Salesman, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Boots (Box 1)
  - Boots in Hot Panties, by Oliver Droopydrawers (Box 3)
  - Boots Gets Hot in the Pants (Box 1)
  - Boots in Love's Labor Lost, by Upyer Brown (Box 1)
  - Boots in Saved, by Iva Biggun (Box 1)
  - Boots in Someone to Love! (Box 1)
  - Boy What a Dream! (Box 1)
  - Brenda Breeze (Box 1)
  - Bunky in The Nursemaid, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Capt. Marvel in Manpower (Box 1)
  - Charlie McCarthy in Using a Wooden One, by Feelma Box (Box 1)
  - Claudette Coal-Bin in Bigger Yet, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Clowning Circus Clown (Box 1)
  - Count Screwloose in Decoyed, 2 variations of same copy (Box 1)
  - Dagwood in The Decoy (Box 1)
  - Dagwood in The Facts of Life, by Luke Atmine (Box 1)
  - Dagwood Has a Family Party! (Box 1)
  - Dagwood in Two Sales, by Loos E. Nutz (Box 1)
  - Dan Dunn Secret Operative 48 (Box 1)
  - Dan Dunn, by Ophelia Pratt (Box 1)
  - Dan Dunn: Crowded with Sex and Action! (Box 1)
  - Dave in Uts-Nay, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - A Day at Home with the Mrs. (Box 1)
  - Denny Dimwit Meets Lana Turnover (Box 1)
  - Denny Dimwit Meets Mae West (Box 1)
  - Denny Dimwit in Taught a Lesson (Box 1)
  - Dick and Sam Get the Payoff (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy in Booster Sal (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy's "Dick" (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy in Disguise, by Hassan Ben Dere (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy in The Evidence (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy Meets Shorty, - The Sheepherder (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy in Missing, by Cedrick Bowelrust (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy in Official Business (Box 1)
  - Dick Tracy in The Smuggler (Box 1)
  - Dinah Proves Her Love for Ozark (Box 1)
  - Ding Dang Doo (Box 1)
  - Dinglehoofer und his dog Adolph (Box 1)
  - Dixie Dugan (Box 1)
  - Dixie Dugan in Imitation of Life (Box 1)
  - Dixie Dugan in Old Reliable, by Albee Shitte (Box 1)
  - Dixie Dugan in The Salesman, by Maida Mann (Box 1)
  - Dixie Dugan in Very Potent VI,by Torrid Tessie, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Doc Gets All Tangled Up!! (Box 1)
  - Doctor Makes a Rabit Test (Box 1)
  - Dora (Box 1)
  - Dorothy Lamour in Purple Passion in the South Seas, by Dewey Twa (Box 1)
  - Dumb Dora (Box 1)
  - Dumb Dora, by Kant Takit, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Dumb Dora V, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Dumb Dora Asslifted by Barney Google, by Upum Fuckum, 4 copies (Box 1)
  - Dumb Dora Get's Her Man (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders, by Letta Laye, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders and Blackie (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders in The Holdup (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders in Running Wild (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders in Such a Grief, by Iva Snatch, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders in Tsk-Tsk, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Ella Cinders and Jiggs in The Dupe, by Stif-Stuf Studios (Box 1)
  - Elmer the Clodhopper, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Etta Kett in Endorsed, by Rub Matocas (Box 1)
  - Eugene the Jeep in Precaution (Box 1)
  - Experience of a Chambermaid and other cartoon jokes (Box 1)
  - The Farmer's Daughter, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Favorite Party Jokes (Box 2)
  - Foozy in The Decoy (Box 1)
  - Fireman Save my Gal (Box 1)
  - Flash Gordon in Red-Hot, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Freckles and his Friends, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Freckles and his Girl (Box 1)
  - The Frigidaire Salesman, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Fritzi Ritz in Insult (Box 1)
  - Fritzi Ritz in Kisses for Sale, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Fritzi Ritz in So This is Hollywood (Box 1)
  - Fritzi Ritz in Straight from the Shoulder (Box 1)
  - The Fuller Brush Man (Box 1)
  - Gasoline Alley or Uncle Walt (Box 1)
  - Gasoline Alley Adventures of Hope (Box 1)
  - Gasoline Alley Hope's Diary (Box 1)
  - Gasoline Alley Skeezix Plows Hopes Hole Hard (Box 1)
  - Geezil in Gimme Beck, by Vera Hott, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Mr. Geezil the Shoe Cobbler (Box 1)
  - Geo. Bungle, by E. Nawder Titzoff (Box 1)
  - George and Harry in Doing Things (Box 1)
  - Georgie and Wifie in All of a Sudden, by Tobasco Pub. Co. (Box 1)
  - Gert Gabbo (Box 1)
  - Ginger Rogers in Hot Panties (Box 1)
  - Good Clean Fun Sizzling with Wit and Humor, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Gordo (Box 1)
  - Gracie Claims (Box 3)
  - Greta Gabo (Box 1)
  - Grumpy and Snow White in A Changed Man, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - The Gumps Oh Min!, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - [Gus and Gussie] (Box 1)
  - Gypsy Rose Lee at the Author's Club (Box 1)
  - Hairbreadth Harry in The Rescue, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - The Hall-Room Boys at the Masked Ball (Box 1)
  - Hans and Fritz Der Teacher (Box 1)
  - Hans and Fritz Meet a Hootchie Cootchie (Box 1)
  - Happy Hooligan (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen, by Peter Dout (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen and Shadow in The Big Dick (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen Conquers a Virgin (the rat) (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen Gets his First Piece of Ass at Hotel La Whore (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen and his Girl in One Good Turn (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen featuring Shadow in "Spellbound", 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen in Sugar Bowl, by U.R.A. Muffdriver (Box 1)
  - Harold Teen in That Tired Feeling (Box 1)
  - He Didn't Speak French (Box 1)
  - He Was Scared Stiff and She Was Happy, 2 copies (Box 1)
  - He Wouldn't Open It (Box 1)
  - Heet Fairy Prince (Box 1)
  - Henry in The Only Way (Box 1)
  - The Hill-Billy, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Hot Rod the Hep Cat (Box 1)
  - How to Keep from Growing Old (Box 1)
  - Ingrid Bergman in Stag Star (Box 2)
  - The Insurance Salesman, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Irene Dumb in Considerate (Box 2)
  - It Feels So Good with Ben Blue (Box 2)
  - It Was Perfect (Box 2)
  - Jack Bimpsey (Box 2)
  - Jean Harlot in A Poor Fit (Box 2)
  - Jeannie Comes in a Bottle (Box 2)
  - Jeem Londos in The Groan and Grunt Idol (Box 2)
  - Jesse James in Might (Box 2)
  - Jiggs (Box 2)
  - Jiggs, by Ophelia T. Wart, 3 copies (Box 2)
  - Jiggs in At the Fair, by Puss Trubble (Box 2)
  - Jiggs in Phew (Box 2)
  - Jiggs in Wotta Dream (Box 2)
  - Joan Dumbell in Looking Ahead (Box 2)
  - Joe Jinks (Box 2)
  - Joe Jinks in I Can Try (Box 2)
  - Joe Louis The Pride of Harlem (Box 2)
  - Joe Penner Wants to Buy a Fuck (Box 2)
  - Joe Palooka, by Jose Clapjob (Box 2)
  - Joe Palooka, presented by Whotta Kavity (Box 2)
  - Joe Palooka in The Champ (Box 2)
  - Joe Palooka with Knobby, by Stoop N. Takit, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - John Dillinger in A Hasty Exit (Box 2)
  - John L. Sullivan The Boston Strong Boy (Box 2)
  - Judge Puffle in Paid, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Jungle Jim in Lil Goes Straight, 3 copies (Box 2)
  - J. Wellington Wimpy in Back to His First Love, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - J. Wellington Wimpy in Beg Pardon (Box 2)
  - J. Wellington Wimpy in Beg Pardon, I'd Rather Fuck (Box 2)
  - J. Wellington Wimpy You Bring the Ducks, by Corn Hole Productions (Box 2)
  - Kathrine Hepbern in Belle of the Hills (Box 2)
  - Kaintuck Hellbellies: A Saga of the Hills, by Pratfeel and M.F. Coys (Box 2)
  - Kansas City Kitty, 4 copies (Box 2)
  - Radio's Kate Smitz (Box 2)
  - The Katzenjammers in Shipwrecked, by Diddle Daley (Box 2)
  - Kayo and Mamie in Juicy Stuff, presented by Zilck Bros. (Box 2)
  - The Kid Sister, by Upyer Brown (Box 2)
  - Killer Burke in Out! (Box 2)
  - Kip and Mac and other cartoon jokes (Box 2)
  - Kiss Me Again (Box 2)
  - Knock Before You Come In (Box 2)
  - Laughs de Luxe (Box 2)
  - Laurel and Hardy (Box 2)
  - Legs Diamond in Strip Poker (Box 2)
  - Lene Tooney the Smart Boy (Box 2)
  - Les Extases, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - A Lesson in Love with Charlie McCarthy (Box 2)
  - Lil Abner, by Lucy Dooplewot (Box 2)
  - Lil Abner in Aunts in the Pants, by U. Shoveme I. Suckeme (Box 2)
  - Little Annie Rooney (Box 2)
  - The Little King in Every Man for Himself, by Fyst Phrigger (Box 2)
  - The Little Ol' Breadwinner, by Ima Cunteater (Box 2)
  - The Lonely Widow (Box 2)
  - Louie, by Jockoffski (Box 2)
  - Luke McGlook in The Smart Boy (Box 2)
  - Mae Breast in A Last Resort, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Mae West Gets Fucked, by Flash Gordon (Box 2)
  - Maggie (Box 2)
  - Maggie Buys a New Hat (Box 2)
  - Maggie in Gay Maid (Box 2)
  - Maggie in the 19th hole (Box 2)
  - Major Hoople, by Alex Dragon (Box 2)
  - Major Hoople in The Birth of a Nation, by Otto Satcheless (Box 2)
  - Major Hoople in Phht (Box 2)
  - Major Hoople in What Would You Do?, by Oliver Crappe (Box 2)
  - Marie the French Maid (Box 2)
  - Max Beer in The Lady's Man (Box 2)
  - Max Smellin (Box 2)
  - Mickey Finn in First Aid (Box 2)
  - Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck (Box 2)
  - Mister Breger in Fucked Again (Box 2)
  - Mister Bull in The Big Shot (Box 2)
  - Molly Had It! (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins in Help!, by Peter B. Everhard, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins and Kayo (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins featuring Kayo in Kayo Fucks Mamie (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins in Nerts (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins N.Y. Daily News Rape Case (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins in Moon and Kaayo Goes in for Fucking (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins and Popeye in Stepping Out, by J. Souerballs (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins in Treat 'em with Kindness (Box 2)
  - Moon Mullins in The 9* Pullout, by Joe Siff (Box 2)
  - The Mullins Family in Resale Value (Box 2)
  - Mr. Bregger is Sold on TV (Box 2)
  - The Nebbs (Box 2)
  - The Nebbs in The Dreamer (Box 2)
  - Ophelia Pratte presents Simp O'Dill in Idle Moments (Box 2)
  - Oh Doctor! (Box 2)
  - The Old Witch Works Her Charms (Box 2)
  - Orphan Annie in The Snooper (Box 2)
  - Patsy Kelly Gets Shot in the Ass with Romance (Box 2)
  - Patsy Kelly in She Got Her Man (Box 2)
  - Peaches and Downing and other cartoon jokes (Box 2)
  - The Tramp Pete in Help!, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Pete in No Help Needed (Box 2)
  - Pete in No Pay (Box 2)
  - Pete The Tramp, 5 copies (Box 2)
  - Phil Fumble (Box 2)
  - Phil Fumble in He Done Her Wrong, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - The Plumbers Delight with Marie Wilson (Box 2)
  - Polly in It's Really an Art (Box 2)
  - Poop-deck Pappy in Bolls (Box 2)
  - Popeye, by Sheza Floppe (Box 2)
  - Popeye, by Weeken Willin (Box 2)
  - Popeye in The Art of Love, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Popeye in Stepping Out, by Phelta Puss (Box 2)
  - Popeye Pops his Ship Load (Box 2)
  - Popeye the Sailor Man!, by Coxswain Pissincreek (Box 2)
  - Popeye the Sailor in (Box 2)
  - Popeye the Sailor in Rowing in the Ocean (Box 2)
  - Popeye the Sailor in A Russian Hard On (Box 2)
  - Popeye the Sailor in Snatch Snatcher (Box 2)
  - Popeye in Pink Passion (Box 2)
  - Popeye in To the Rescue (Box 2)
  - Position is Everything in Life with Lew Lehr, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Primo Canary in Push 'Em Up (Box 2)
  - Psychology in One Easy Lesson, by Joe Siff (Box 2)
  - Radio Salesman, 3 copies (Box 2)
  - The Real Silk Hosiery Salesman, by Whattawat and Co., 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Reel Fun (Box 2)
  - Relentless Rudolph in High Finance (Box 2)
  - Remember Way Back When, 3 copies (Box 2)
  - Rosie's Beau, by E.T. Inth'Loop, 3 copies (Box 2)
  - The Rubber Salesman, 3 copies (Box 2)
  - Rubinoff and his Etchings in Play This One On Your Violin, by Holdin Hissen (Box 2)
  - Ruth Edding in Thrifty Baby (Box 2)
  - Sad Sack Meets Susie Foque (Box 2)
  - Sadie and the Milkman, 4 copies (Box 2)
  - Salesman Sam in the Big Game Hunter (Box 2)
  - Sappo with Prof. O.G. Whattaschnozzle (Box 2)
  - Sappo in Haunted, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Sappo with Prof O.G. Whattaschnozzle, by Lipsmit Bros. (Box 2)
  - Schnozzles, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - A Scotchman's Hole in One (Box 2)
  - She Got the Job (Box 2)
  - She Lost It at the Astor (Box 2)
  - She Loved It with W.C. Fields, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - She Saw the Director With the Office Boy's Help (Box 2)
  - She Was Dumb like a Fox (Box 2)
  - Sheer Nonsense (Box 2)
  - She Will be Coming around the Mountain, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Skeezix, by Whattaprick Inc. (Box 2)
  - Skippy in Hot and Hairy (Box 2)
  - Sleepy and Sneezy Go to Town (Box 2)
  - Smiles to Cure the Blues (Box 2)
  - Smilin' Jack in Air Necking, by Tu Yung Tu (Box 2)
  - Smilin' Jack in Close Up (Box 2)
  - Smilin' Jack in Flying High (Box 2)
  - Smilin' Jack in Pick Me Up An' Run (Box 2)
  - Smokey, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Snow White Makes Bashful Grow Bold!! And He Loves It! (Box 2)
  - Snuffy, by Iva Wopper, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Snuffy Smithy Learns a New Game (Box 2)
  - Spider-Man in Takes Off The Mask! (Box 3)
  - Stella Clinker in Too Weak (Box 3)
  - Steve Canyon in A Hotel Room (Box 3)
  - A Strain on the Family Life, by G. Howitt Hoyts (Box 3)
  - Strange as it Seems (Box 3)
  - Streaky, 3 copies (Box 3)
  - Sub-Mariner in Water Sport (Box 3)
  - Sweeney and Son in Sonny Fucks Around (Box 3)
  - Sylvia Kidney in False Rumors, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Taxi Driver, 3 copies (Box 3)
  - That Son-in-Law of Pa's (Box 3)
  - That's My Pop, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - That's My Pop, by Fanny Warmer, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - There's No Harm in Asking She May Say Yes! (Box 3)
  - Terry and the Pirates (Box 3)
  - Tillie in The Artist (Box 3)
  - Tillie in Easy Picking, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Tillie and Mac (Box 3)
  - Tillie and Mack with Maggie (Box 3)
  - Tillie and Mack with Mr. Simpkins and Bubbles, 3 copies (Box 3)
  - Nerts to You with Tillie and Mack, by Otto Whataprick (Box 3)
  - Tillie the Toiler in Ooooh-Hmm-Daddy (Box 3)
  - Tillie the Toiler in Ruined, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Toots and Casper, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Toots and Casper Go to a Circus (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    photocopy
  - Toots and Jiggs and other cartoon jokes (Box 3)
  - Uncle Bim and Mille, by Bagg O. Nutts (Box 3)
  - Uncle Phil in Blah (Box 3)
  - Uncle Willie (Box 3)
  - Uncle Willie and Moon in Masquerade, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Untitled, 3 items 2 versions; 3 books (Box 3)
  - Upom U. Freud in Orifice Call, by Will U. Rimmum (Box 3)
  - The Vacuum Cleaner Man (Box 3)
  - Wally in the Bath (Box 3)
  - Wally and the French Ambassador (Box 3)
  - Wally and the King (Box 3)
  - Wally and the Pageboy, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Wally and the Sultan (Box 3)
  - Wally in the Bath (Box 3)
  - The Webbs 6 (Box 3)
  - The Webbs VIII (Box 3)
  - The Wicked Queen Who Started This Whole Damned Business!!! (Box 3)
  - William Powell and Myrna Loy in Nuts to Will Hays, by Hardon Ever (Box 3)
  - Wimpy in Deformed, by Lydia Liverpad, 4 copies (Box 3)
  - Wimpy in Only Love Baby, by A Jerkoff Production (Box 3)
  - Wimpy in The Temptress, by Long Dong (Box 3)
  - Winnie Winkle in Strictly Business (Box 3)
  - Winnie Winkle in The Stenog (Box 3)
  - Winnie Winkle in The Stenog (Box 3)
  - WMP. Mullins Kayo and Mamie in Juicy Stuff, by Zitch Bros, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Wonder Woman meets Superman (Box 3)
  - Woozy Winks Ablely Assisted by Plasticman (Box 3)
  - Yes, We Have No Bananas, 2 copies (Box 3)
- Manuscript Materials, 2
  - Sketches, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Sketches of Minnie Ha-Cha, Kitty Cornpone, and Wahoo (Box 4)
  - Sketches of Li'l Abner and Daisy Mae (Box 4)
  - Fritzi Ritz in Kisses for Sale drafts (Box 4)
- Printed materials about Tijuana Bibles, 1971-1998, 3
  - Dirty Little Sex Cartoons. Argyle Books: Los Angeles, Calif. 1972. (Box 4)
  - Douglas, John. Hot Little Comics: Volume One. Monogram Publications, Inc. 1972. (Box 4)
  - Douglas, John. Hot Little Comics: Volume Two. Monogram Publications, Inc. 1972. (Box 4)
  - Dowers, Michael, ed. The Tijuana Bibles: America's Forgotten Comic Strips, Volume I. Eros Comix: Seattle, Washington. 1998. (Box 4)
  - Dowers, Michael, ed. The Tijuana Bibles: America's Forgotten Comic Strips, Volume II. Eros Comix: Seattle, Washington. 1998. (Box 4)
  - Dowers, Michael, ed. The Tijuana Bibles: America's Forgotten Comic Strips, Volume III. Eros Comix: Seattle, Washington. 1998. (Box 4)
  - Gilmore, Donald H. Sex in Comics: A History of the Eight Pagers, Volume 4. Greenleaf Classic, Inc.: San Diego, Calif. 1971. (Box 4)
  - Little "Dirty" Comics. Socio Library: Resada Calif. 1976. (Box 4)
  - More Dirty Little Sex Cartoons. PHE Inc. 1983. (Box 4)
  - More Little "Dirty" Comics: Volume Two. Socio Library: Resada, Calif. 1971. (Box 4)
  - Murky R. and J. B. Randy. The Tia Juana Bible Revival, Volume One: "Hot Nuts." Penetrating Pubs., Inc.: Blue Balls, Penn. 1977. (Box 4)
  - Murky R. and J. B. Randy. The Tia Juana Bible Revival, Volume Two: "Under the Stars in Hollywood." Paramounds Prod.: Hooker, Calif. 1977. (Box 4)
  - Raymond, Otis. An Illustrated History of Sex Comic Classics, Volume I. Comic Classics: New York, NY. 1972. (Box 4)
  - Raymond, Otis. An Illustrated History of Sex Comic Classics, Volume II. Comic Classics: New York, NY. 1972. (Box 4)
  - Reynolds, John J. Famous Sex Comics. Socio Library: Resada, Calif. 1976. (Box 4)